Divya Chandran

Contact

+49 15124403447

divya.chandran10@gmail.com

Frankfurt am Main, Germany





Skills

Technologies:

- Python
- HTML & CSS
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Google Cloud Platform
- CI/CD (GitHub Actions)
- REST API, Fast API
- Docker
- Heroku
- C, C++, Java
- Postman
- Matplotlib (Basics)

Frameworks:

- Django
- Django Rest Framework

Version Controls

• Git

Databases

- PostgreSQL
- SQL

Others:

- Agile Development
- Test Driven Development
- Project Management
- Pair Programming

Soft skills

- Problem-solver
- Decision maker
- Motivator
- Adaptable
- Inclusive

Language

English - Professional proficiency

German - Limited working proficiency

Tamil - Native

Telugu - Mother tongue



Python developer who recently graduated a 1-year intensive training in Backend Programming. Seeking a position to apply experience from testing, marketing, teaching, backend development to challenge myself and deliver solution-oriented approaches with keen attention to details.

Education

Mar 2022 - Apr 2023

DCI Digital Career Institute gGmbH I Frankfurt am Main, Germany

Full-time intensive one year remote training on Python, Databases, Django Framework, APIs, Cloud services and Version control systems with including completion of multiple small projects and one final large practical project to showcase programming skills.

Lingoda - Online Training on German Language | B2.2

Jan 2019 - Jun 2020

ASB Lehrerkooperative gGmbH | Frankfurt am Main, Germany Certified - Full time training on German Language | A1 - B1

Sep 2006 - May 2010

Anna University | Chennai, India Bachelor of Technology - Information Technology

Experience

Jun 2017 - Dec 2017

Bharat International School | Krishnagiri, India

Computer Science Teacher

- Delivered engaging curriculum through diverse methods of classroom instruction, computer lab
 activities. Trained and developed students' skills in word-processing, spreadsheet and scratch
 programs.
- Tested and evaluated 500+ students' progress to determine effectiveness and impact of teaching methods, materials and projects.
- Attended professional development technology courses to increase knowledge base and learn new
 information. Invigilated and graded projects, quizzes and examinations. Communicated with students
 to discuss progress and need for tutoring and extra assistance.

Nov 2015 - May 2017

Self-employed

• Managed small-scale textile business.

Nov 2010 - Apr 2013

HCL Technologies Ltd | Chennai, India

Software Engineer [Developer / Tester]

- Designed and updated layouts using HTML, CSS.
- Drafted user story documents by gathering the requirements. Authored and maintained well-organized,
 efficient and successful test cases for entire team. Identified and tracked defects by manually testing the
 application and supported developers in resolving problems by completing additional tests. Recorded test
 results in an Excel Template designed by the clients, detailing testing processes, results and suggestions
 for production team.
- Worked alongside management to develop testing and improvement plans. Interacted with software
 application developers and customer service teams to clarify design specifications, test requirements, and
 address defect resolutions. Transferred knowledge to the new team members. Added values to the
 project by suggesting the added functionalities and received Client appreciation for the same.

Relevant Projects

DCI Digital Career Institute gGmbH I Frankfurt am Main, Germany

Survey Platform

- Grant current and former employees the ability to write an honest and detailed review of their employer as well as facilitate communication between companies and future employees.
- Provides Hybrid solution with Template questions and User created questions.

Share Platform

• An online platform to share products with others under development.

Others

Apr 2013 - Oct 2015

Relocated to Sweden, due to spouse's job. During this period, I explored new places and new culture.

10-Feb-2023